# Sami Mabrouk

Software Engineer | San Diego, CA (Remote) | 858.733.1242 | <a href="mailto:samimabrouk10@gmail.com"><u>samimabrouk10@gmail.com</u></a> | <a href="mailto:https://www.linkedin.com/in/mabrouk10"><u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mabrouk10/</u> | <a href="mailto:https://mabrouk10.github.io/portfolio/">https://mabrouk10.github.io/portfolio/</a> | <a href="mailto:github.com/mabrouk10"><u>github.com/mabrouk10</u></a>

### **Summary**

Software Engineer with strong analytical and logical skills dedicated to building and optimizing creative web applications that provide intuitive user experiences. Strong skills developed in critical thinking, leadership, communication and teamwork from previous work experiences as a Research Associate, Full Stack Developer Intern and Software QA Analyst.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages:

- JavaScript
- Rubv
- HTML
- CSS
- Java

Frameworks:

- React
- Ruby on Rails

Databases:

PostgreSQL

Active Record

Testina:

- lest
- Rspec

*Version Control:* 

• Git

Other related skills:

- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Discrete Mathematics
- Statistics
- JIRA/Confluence

**Experience** 

**LEARN Academy** 

November 2020 - Present

Software Engineer in Training

- 12 week full-time web development bootcamp that specializes in JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, and PostgreSQL
- In class lectures mixed with extensive pair and mob programming
- Classwork and group projects available on github (<a href="https://github.com/mabrouk10">https://github.com/mabrouk10</a>)
- Completed 480+ hours of direct coding experience
- Obtained proficiency in test-driven development

snaploT

August 2020 - November 2020

Software QA Analyst

- Planned and coordinated testing activities using JIRA and Confluence. Developed, published and implemented test plans to ensure product quality
- Designed traceability matrices, test plans and test scripts for mobile and platform software requirements
- Managed and distributed assets and documentation from creative department to engineering team
- Conducted integration, version, regression, user acceptance testing

Orlando Inc

September 2020 - October 2020

Full Stack Developer Intern

- Learning MEAN development stack (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js) stack to build applications for aviation schools
- Collaborating with UI/UX designers, full stack developers/engineers and CEO to create design decisions, reiterate group objectives and set future goals.

Explora

April 2020 - May 2020

Research Associate

- Formulated and administered test articles through multiple routes in mice (PO, IP, IV, SQ)
- Executed pharmacokinetic studies and disease model development studies in mice
- Routinely performed daily responsibilities in BSL I and BSL II conditions

### **Scripps Research Institute**

December 2018 - June

2019 Research Associate Intern

- Worked in the Remi Martin Fardon Lab. Research focused on drug addiction and relapse.
- Data processing and analysis of lab rat behavior to addictive substances
- Monitoring and facilitating experiments that involved addictive substances.

#### **Other Experience**

Renes

March 2017 – December 2019

Waiter

 Improved communication and relationship skills whilst providing customers exceptional service

Vons

May 2014 – March 2017

Combo Clerk

- Worked in four different departments showcasing skills in adaptability.
- Developed soft skills when working with customers and leading team members

ISSD/MCC

March 2017 – June 2017/January 2019 - March

2019

P.E. Instructor/Head Soccer Coach

- Developed leadership and communication skills when teaching both P.E. and soccer
- Led a team of assistant coaches to execute creative plans for soccer practices as a soccer coach

#### **Education**

#### University of California, San Diego

June 2019

Bachelor of Science: General Biology (Completed)

Minor: Computer Science (In progress unable to register into Upper Div classes due to limited seats in classes)

## Udemy

The Web Developer Bootcamp
The Complete JavaScript Course

*JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Masterclass*